<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
  <title>january1073 News Feed</title>
  <link>https://january1073.github.io/rss.xml</link>
  <description>Updates from january1073</description>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <atom:link href="https://january1073.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 18:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>

  <item>
    <title>Cheating Permitted? German Federal Court of Justice Rules on ‘Action Replay II’</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/cheating-permitted-german-federal-court-of-justice-rules-on-action-replay-ii-b1e8e051107c</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/cheating-permitted-german-federal-court-of-justice-rules-on-action-replay-ii-b1e8e051107c</guid>
    <description>In a landmark decision with significant implications for both the video game industry and copyright law, the German Federal Court of Justice (Bundesgerichtshof or BGH) has issued a ruling on the legality of “cheat software.” The case, known as “Action Replay II,” has established a key distinction between modifying a game’s underlying code and simply manipulating its in-game data...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>The EU Cyber Resilience Act: Raising the Bar for Digital Product Security</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/the-eu-cyber-resilience-act-raising-the-bar-for-digital-product-security-e7d643d0c897</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/the-eu-cyber-resilience-act-raising-the-bar-for-digital-product-security-e7d643d0c897</guid>
    <description>The Cyber Resilience Act (CRA) entered into force on 10 December 2024, establishing mandatory cybersecurity requirements for all products with digital elements sold in the EU market. While the Act is now law, main obligations apply from 11 December 2027, with some requirements (like incident reporting) taking effect from 11 September 2026...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>darkmailr — Generate realistic, context-aware phishing emails — air-gapped</title>
    <link>https://infosecwriteups.com/darkmailr-generate-realistic-context-aware-phishing-emails-air-gapped-d3cc88457dab</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://infosecwriteups.com/darkmailr-generate-realistic-context-aware-phishing-emails-air-gapped-d3cc88457dab</guid>
    <description>darkmailr is a self-hosted, offline phishing simulation tool that uses open-source LLMs (via Ollama) to generate realistic, context-aware phishing emails for red team exercises, security awareness training, and prompt injection testing...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Red Team Adaptation in the Age of Agentic AI — A Game Theory Playbook for Offensive Security</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/red-team-adaptation-in-the-age-of-agentic-ai-61ab4993386e</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/red-team-adaptation-in-the-age-of-agentic-ai-61ab4993386e</guid>
    <description>The game has changed. As a red teamer, you've mastered the art of thinking like your adversaries, exploiting human psychology, and finding the unexpected path through seemingly impenetrable defenses. But now you're facing something entirely different: agentic AI systems that don't get tired, don't make emotional decisions, and can process information at speeds that make your fastest reconnaissance look glacial...</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>NIS 2: Wie geht es jetzt weiter in Deutschland?</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/nis-2-wie-geht-es-jetzt-weiter-in-deutschland-57df71d74203</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/nis-2-wie-geht-es-jetzt-weiter-in-deutschland-57df71d74203</guid>
    <description>Die Cybersicherheitslage in Deutschland ist angespannt, mit einem Höchststand an Cybercrime-Fällen in 2024 und astronomischen finanziellen Schäden, während viele Unternehmen unzureichend vorbereitet sind und die NIS-2-Richtlinie kaum kennen...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Cleartext Protocols 101: How to Connect Anonymously to FTP, Telnet, and rsync</title>
    <link>https://osintteam.blog/cleartext-protocols-101-how-to-connect-anonymously-to-ftp-telnet-and-rsync-2c1001dcbdb0</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://osintteam.blog/cleartext-protocols-101-how-to-connect-anonymously-to-ftp-telnet-and-rsync-2c1001dcbdb0</guid>
    <description>Welcome back to the "100s Series"! After mastering network reconnaissance with tcpdump, Wireshark, and Nmap, it's time to explore what happens when you find open services. While modern security practices emphasize encryption and authentication, legacy cleartext protocols still lurk in corporate networks, IoT devices, and forgotten systems. File Transport Protocol (FTP), Telnet, and rsync often expose sensitive data through misconfigured anonymous access, default credentials, and unprotected file shares. This article will teach you to identify, access, and extract intelligence from such cleartext protocol implementations...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Your Client’s Data Is Not Safe with Microsoft — And You Know It</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/your-clients-data-is-not-safe-with-microsoft-and-you-know-it-1fa88fdbdcbb</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/your-clients-data-is-not-safe-with-microsoft-and-you-know-it-1fa88fdbdcbb</guid>
    <description>EU lawyers are bound not only by the law, but by strict professional duties of confidentiality. Continuing to use the Microsoft ecosystem — which is subject to U.S. surveillance laws and known for opaque data handling practices — may violate core tenets of GDPR, EU Court rulings, and professional codes. The legal profession must move toward self-hosted, open-source, and EU-based services to protect client data and uphold the integrity of their work...</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Nmap 101: Mapping Your Target’s Attack Surface</title>
    <link>https://osintteam.blog/nmap-101-mapping-your-targets-attack-surface-5bae9735c60d</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://osintteam.blog/nmap-101-mapping-your-targets-attack-surface-5bae9735c60d</guid>
    <description>Welcome back to the “100s Series”! After exploring network traffic analysis with tcpdump and Wireshark, it’s time to shift from passive observation to active reconnaissance. Nmap (short for “Network Mapper”) remains a cornerstone tool for network discovery and security auditing, turning hidden network infrastructures into comprehensive maps of potential attack surfaces. This comprehensive walkthrough will teach you to discover, enumerate, and analyze network targets with surgical precision...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Light Mode for Hack The Box</title>
    <link>https://infosecwriteups.com/light-mode-for-hackthebox-bff9ed4c8922</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://infosecwriteups.com/light-mode-for-hackthebox-bff9ed4c8922</guid>
    <description>Hack The Box doesn’t offer a light mode and — as far as I know — doesn’t plan to introduce one. However, especially for HTB Academy, where I sometimes spend hours reading comprehensive modules, I wanted dark text on a light background to reduce eye strain during extended study sessions. After testing several solutions, I found the perfect workaround that every HTB learner should know about...</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Der Pentesting-Vertrag — Checkliste mit Musterklauseln</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/der-pentesting-vertrag-961e19c5860e</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/der-pentesting-vertrag-961e19c5860e</guid>
    <description>Für IT-Sicherheitsunternehmen, die Penetrationstests anbieten oder in Auftrag geben, sind gut strukturierte Verträge essenziell für erfolgreiche Geschäftsbeziehungen. Ein präzise formulierter Pentesting-Vertrag schützt beide Parteien, definiert klare Erwartungen und minimiert rechtliche sowie betriebliche Risiken...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Wireshark 101: Extracting Secrets from Captured Network Data</title>
    <link>https://osintteam.blog/wireshark-101-extracting-secrets-from-captured-network-data-8f40bd3252f9</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://osintteam.blog/wireshark-101-extracting-secrets-from-captured-network-data-8f40bd3252f9</guid>
    <description>Welcome back to the “100s Series”! After our deep dive into the command-line wizardry of tcpdump, it’s time to level up our network analysis game. Wireshark offers a user-friendly graphical approach to network analysis, providing a detailed look at the conversations happening on your network. This walkthrough will equip you with the skills to capture, filter, and analyze data with ease. Get ready to see your network traffic in a whole new light...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>How I Flooded Myself 🫣 — hping3 Against Apache</title>
    <link>https://infosecwriteups.com/how-i-flooded-myself-hping3-against-apache-c518cbab639f</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://infosecwriteups.com/how-i-flooded-myself-hping3-against-apache-c518cbab639f</guid>
    <description>A denial of service (DoS) attack floods a target system with malicious traffic, overwhelming it, and preventing legitimate users from accessing network resources. This I wanted to try at home — attacking my own machine, of course...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>DORA Has Entered the Chat: EU’s New Cyber Rulebook Reshaping Financial Security</title>
    <link>https://infosecwriteups.com/dora-has-entered-the-chat-eus-new-cyber-rulebook-reshaping-financial-security-e2ce7dd95c5d</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://infosecwriteups.com/dora-has-entered-the-chat-eus-new-cyber-rulebook-reshaping-financial-security-e2ce7dd95c5d</guid>
    <description>The EU’s Digital Operational Resilience Act became applicable in January 2025, and it’s changing the game for security professionals in the financial sector. Here’s what you need to know...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>tcpdump 101: Silently Capturing Your Target’s Network Traffic</title>
    <link>https://osintteam.blog/tcpdump-101-silently-capturing-your-targets-network-traffic-76b839e64232</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://osintteam.blog/tcpdump-101-silently-capturing-your-targets-network-traffic-76b839e64232</guid>
    <description>If you can see the packets, you can understand the system — and if you can silently capture them, you’re already halfway in. tcpdump is one of the most precise tools in an attacker’s toolkit, and it’s just as useful for defenders who want to think like one. This article launches my “100s Series,” where I will walk you through key cybersecurity tools and strategies that sharpen your skills for both offense and defense. First up: tcpdump —your entry point to silent monitoring and powerful packet analysis...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>From Panic to Action: How to Recover from a GCP Data Breach</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/respond-and-recover-from-a-data-breach-in-google-cloud-capstone-project-of-the-google-cloud-634e1976fc88</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/respond-and-recover-from-a-data-breach-in-google-cloud-capstone-project-of-the-google-cloud-634e1976fc88</guid>
    <description>For the Google Cloud Cybersecurity Certificate capstone project, in addition to video lectures and multiple-choice questions, I had to complete practical tasks in a Google Cloud lab and create a security incident report...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Finding Flaws 101: Scanning Metasploitable2 with Nessus Pro</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/unmasking-metasploitable2-988d2ed3fe67</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/unmasking-metasploitable2-988d2ed3fe67</guid>
    <description>This write-up outlines the setup and execution of vulnerability scans using Nessus Professional against a Metasploitable2 virtual machine (VM) to demonstrate vulnerability assessment procedures...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Das chinesische Sozialkreditsystem für Unternehmen – Hintergründe und praktische Hinweise</title>
    <link>https://www.springerprofessional.de/das-chinesische-sozialkreditsystem-fuer-unternehmen-hintergruend/18635734</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.springerprofessional.de/das-chinesische-sozialkreditsystem-fuer-unternehmen-hintergruend/18635734</guid>
    <description>Der vorliegende Beitrag erläutert die Hintergründe zur Einführung eines Sozialkreditsystems für Unternehmen in China. Die Autoren geben einen Überblick über die Auswirkungen des neuen Systems und liefern praktische Hinweise für Unternehmen, wie sie sich daran anpassen können... (Paywall)</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

</channel>
</rss>
