<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>january1073 News Feed</title>
  <link>https://january1073.github.io/rss.xml</link>
  <description>Updates from january1073</description>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>

  <item>
    <title>Cheating Permitted? German Federal Court of Justice Rules on ‘Action Replay II’</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/cheating-permitted-german-federal-court-of-justice-rules-on-action-replay-ii-b1e8e051107c</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/cheating-permitted-german-federal-court-of-justice-rules-on-action-replay-ii-b1e8e051107c</guid>
    <description>In a landmark decision with significant implications for both the video game industry and copyright law, the German Federal Court of Justice (Bundesgerichtshof or BGH) has issued a ruling on the legality of “cheat software.” The case, known as “Action Replay II,” has established a key distinction between modifying a game’s underlying code and simply manipulating its in-game data...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>The EU Cyber Resilience Act: Raising the Bar for Digital Product Security</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/the-eu-cyber-resilience-act-raising-the-bar-for-digital-product-security-e7d643d0c897</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/the-eu-cyber-resilience-act-raising-the-bar-for-digital-product-security-e7d643d0c897</guid>
    <description>The Cyber Resilience Act (CRA) entered into force on 10 December 2024, establishing mandatory cybersecurity requirements for all products with digital elements sold in the EU market. While the Act is now law, main obligations apply from 11 December 2027, with some requirements (like incident reporting) taking effect from 11 September 2026...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>darkmailr — Generate realistic, context-aware phishing emails — air-gapped</title>
    <link>https://infosecwriteups.com/darkmailr-generate-realistic-context-aware-phishing-emails-air-gapped-d3cc88457dab</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://infosecwriteups.com/darkmailr-generate-realistic-context-aware-phishing-emails-air-gapped-d3cc88457dab</guid>
    <description>darkmailr is a self-hosted, offline phishing simulation tool that uses open-source LLMs (via Ollama) to generate realistic, context-aware phishing emails for red team exercises, security awareness training, and prompt injection testing...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Red Team Adaptation in the Age of Agentic AI — A Game Theory Playbook for Offensive Security</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/red-team-adaptation-in-the-age-of-agentic-ai-61ab4993386e</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/red-team-adaptation-in-the-age-of-agentic-ai-61ab4993386e</guid>
    <description>The game has changed. As a red teamer, you've mastered the art of thinking like your adversaries, exploiting human psychology, and finding the unexpected path through seemingly impenetrable defenses. But now you're facing something entirely different: agentic AI systems that don't get tired, don't make emotional decisions, and can process information at speeds that make your fastest reconnaissance look glacial...</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>NIS 2: Wie geht es jetzt weiter in Deutschland?</title>
    <link>https://january1073.medium.com/nis-2-wie-geht-es-jetzt-weiter-in-deutschland-57df71d74203</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://january1073.medium.com/nis-2-wie-geht-es-jetzt-weiter-in-deutschland-57df71d74203</guid>
    <description>Die Cybersicherheitslage in Deutschland ist angespannt, mit einem Höchststand an Cybercrime-Fällen in 2024 und astronomischen finanziellen Schäden, während viele Unternehmen unzureichend vorbereitet sind und die NIS-2-Richtlinie kaum kennen...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Cleartext Protocols 101: How to Connect Anonymously to FTP, Telnet, and rsync</title>
    <link>https://osintteam.blog/cleartext-protocols-101-how-to-connect-anonymously-to-ftp-telnet-and-rsync-2c1001dcbdb0</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://osintteam.blog/cleartext-protocols-101-how-to-connect-anonymously-to-ftp-telnet-and-rsync-2c1001dcbdb0</guid>
    <description>Welcome back to the "100s Series"! After mastering network reconnaissance with tcpdump, Wireshark, and Nmap, it's time to explore what happens when you find open services. While modern security practices emphasize encryption and authentication, legacy cleartext protocols still lurk in corporate networks, IoT devices, and forgotten systems. File Transport Protocol (FTP), Telnet, and rsync often expose sensitive data through misconfigured anonymous access, default credentials, and unprotected file shares. This article will teach you to identify, access, and extract intelligence from such cleartext protocol implementations...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>5-Minute Guide to Binary Exploitation — ret2win with GDB and pwntools</title>
    <link>https://infosecwriteups.com/5-minute-guide-to-binary-exploitation-ret2win-with-gdb-and-pwntools-22c4bc043293</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://infosecwriteups.com/5-minute-guide-to-binary-exploitation-ret2win-with-gdb-and-pwntools-22c4bc043293</guid>
    <description>This article introduces you to the basic concept of return-to-win (ret2win) exploitation, where the goal is to redirect execution flow to a desired function using a buffer overflow. It walks you through a simple binary with no stack canaries, NX disabled, and no PIE — making it a great playground for getting started with classic ROP-based techniques...</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>

</channel>
</rss>
